The journey begins.
The Croods is a animation, adventure, family film directed by Kirk DeMicco.
The prehistoric Croods family live in a particularly dangerous moment in time.
Patriarch Grug, his mate Ugga, teenage daughter Eep, son Thunk, and feisty
Gran gather food by day and huddle together in a cave at night.
When a more evolved caveman named Guy arrives on the scene, Grug is distrustful, but it soon
becomes apparent that Guy is correct about the impending destruction of their world.
Grug (voice), played by Nicolas Cage.
Eep (voice), played by Emma Stone.
Guy (voice), played by Ryan Reynolds.
Ugga (voice), played by Catherine Keener.
Gran (voice), played by Cloris Leachman.
Thunk (voice), played by Clark Duke.
The Croods is a 2013 American animated adventure comedy film
written and directed by Chris Sanders and Kirk DeMicco.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, it stars the voices of Nicolas Cage, Emma Stone,
Ryan Reynolds, Catherine Keener, Clark Duke, and Cloris Leachman.
It is set in a fictional prehistoric Pliocene era known as "The Croodaceous" where Grug, patriarch of the Croods, is threatened by the arrival of
a genius named Guy, who comes up with revolutionary new inventions as they trek through a dangerous land in search of a new home.
The film premiered at the 63rd Berlin International Film Festival on February 15, 2013,
and was released in the United States on March 22 by 20th Century Fox.
It received generally positive reviews, and grossed $587
million on a budget of $135–175 million.
It was nominated for an Academy Award and a Golden
Globe for Best Animated Feature.
The film launched a franchise, consisting of two television series, Dawn of the Croods (2015)
and The Croods: Family Tree (2021), and a sequel, The Croods: A New Age (2020).
The film explores themes of daughter, parent child
relationship, stone age, father, prehistory.
The tone is lighthearted.